

Alexandria, VA 22305 🏠 (908) 937-8587 📞

shakira.r.weir@gmail.com ⊠

LinkedIn • Portfolio • GitHub ⊕



I am a web developer motivated by opportunities to find creative and efficient solutions to realword problems. My background in writing, education and tech fuel my desire to create interactive products that will enrich the human experience. I am excited to use my skills to transform words and ideas into an interactive, digital reality.

## **EXPERIENCE**

### Web Development Immersive

GENERAL ASSEMBLY December 2018 - present

Building fluency in full-stack web development by completing an intensive 500-hour, three-month program focused on common best practices, tools and methodologies in objectoriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and test-driven development. Select projects:

- BookHub | GitHub A home library management app for users to catalog and share book collections JavaScript | HTML | CSS | MongoDB | Express.JS Node.JS | Handlebars | Passport | API | mLab
- The Fun Budget Tool | GitHub A personal finance app for users to track their personal finances MongoDB | Express | React | Node | mLab

## Information System Technician

US COAST GUARD

2015-2019

Network Analyst, Enterprise Operations Center

- Managed 25+ network incidents and outages daily
- Analyzed bandwidth traffic to determine network latency
- Coordinated rapid response and repair of network outages, ensuring quick restoration of operations in 70% of 30+ units directly impacted by Hurricanes Irma & Harvey CND Analyst, Cyber Security Operations Center
- Monitored CG network for cyber-related threats and malware alerts. Investigated security violations
- Retrieved emails and documents for legal investigations

#### Science Teacher

NORTH STAR ACADEMY-VAILSBURG MIDDLE SCHOOL 2013-2014

- Collected data (assessments, assignments, proficiency level) from 90+ students to create individualized lesson plans
- Fostered relationships with stakeholders (students, parents, advisors) through mail merges and one-on-one meetings to increase engagement and achieve mastery goals.

#### SKILLS

Programming Languages

JavaScript

Front End Development HTML5 | CSS3 | Sass Bootstrap | Materialize | API Handlebars | React

Back End Development NodeJS | Express | MVC RESTful APIs | MongoDB mLab | Mongoose | AJAX

Authentication Passport | Jason Web Token

**Development Tools** Git | GitHub | Heroku Wireframing

# **EDUCATION**

General Assembly 2019 Web Development Immersive

University of Massachusetts 2018 Amherst Certificate in Journalism

St. John's University 2009 B.S., Biological Science Minor - Sociology